<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AP United States History on Notes</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apush/</link><description>Recent content in AP United States History on Notes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apush/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>APUSH Period 7</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apush/period-7/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apush/period-7/</guid><description>Imperialism Reasons for imperialism Closing of the frontier Economic motives Racial theories Impacts of imperialism Spanish-American War
Causes
Yellow journalism (USS Maine) Imperialism, motive to protect Cubans and Filipinos Business interests with Cuba US gained Guam, Puerto Rico, Philippines
Insurrection in PH Debates about imperialism
Similar to interventionists and isolationists Progressive Era Progressives tended to be
Urban Middle Class Women Progressives sought to
Reform society socially and politically Use the federal government</description></item><item><title>APUSH Period 6</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apush/period-6/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apush/period-6/</guid><description>Gilded Age **
Social Effects More women more educated
As a result, more job opportunities opened for women Reform Edward Bellamy&amp;#39;s Looking Backward Was it possible to have an industrial society without great inequality?
Social Darwinists: no Responses to inequality New economic systems
Socialism
No private property Eugene V. Debs Single tax
Henry George Replace all other taxes with a single tax on the value of land Tax would pay for all necessary government expenditures Responses to urban problems Settlement house movement Social Gospel movement City Beautiful movement Politics Change and Continuity Work and business 1865 Farming, sharecropping Segregation Working in mills 1898 Farming and sharecropping Segregation Women&amp;#39;s and children&amp;#39;s labor Unions Mass production Living and migration patterns 1865 Most immigrants from Northern and Western Europe 20% of Americans lived in cities Some urban density and poverty 1898 Most immigrants from Southern and Eastern Europe 40% of Americans lived in cities Black migration High urban density and poverty Culture and ideas 1865 Nativism Intense push for racial equality Laissez-faire 1898 Nativism Little interest in racial equality Social Darwinism Review Topics Emergence of monopolies Social Darwinism Reasons for migration to cities New South New Immigration Labor unions The Grange Populists Westward Expansion</description></item><item><title>APUSH Period 5</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apush/period-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apush/period-5/</guid><description>Manifest Destiny Based on racial and cultural superiority Main focus of political debates Acquiring territory Mexican-American War Wilmot Proviso
Debates over slavery Impacts of Expansion Environmental changes Settlement of Indian lands Old Immigrants, pre-Civil War
Germans Irish Faced nativism
Know-nothing party Westward Expansion Opportunities out West
Increased due to legislation promoting economic development
Homestead Act of 1862 Impacts Conflicts with Hispanics and Natives
Sand Creek Massacre Little Big Horn North vs South North</description></item><item><title>APUSH Period 4</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apush/period-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apush/period-4/</guid><description>Increased Democracy and Government Relationships Emergence of Political Parties
Federalists vs. Democratic-Republican (1790s)
Hamilton vs. Jefferson Democrats vs. Whigs (1830s - 1850s)
Jackson vs. Clay Supreme Court increased the power of the federal government over states
McCulloch v. Maryland Worcester v. Georgia Growth of market economy
Embargo Act of 1807 Nullification Crisis of 1832 South justified slavery as a &amp;#34;positive good&amp;#34; New Institutions 2nd Great Awakening
Stressed importance of achieving perfection Reform movenets</description></item><item><title>Potential LEQ Topics</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apush/potential-leq-topics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apush/potential-leq-topics/</guid><description>Triangular Trade Causes
Desire for goods/trade (economic) Desire to develop colonies (political) Demand for slave labor Effects
Introduction of new crops Development of colonies Further demand for slave labor Exchange of culture Market Revolution Causes and effects are mostly similar; you can interchange causes and effects unless asked to compare the causes and effects Causes
Rapid improvements of transportation and communication Industrial machines and inventions Increased federal power Effects</description></item></channel></rss>