<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AP United States Government on Notes</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apgov/</link><description>Recent content in AP United States Government on Notes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apgov/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Policy Making System</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apgov/policy-making-system/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apgov/policy-making-system/</guid><description>Elitism and Pluralism Although 24 states give voters the ability to directly vote on legislation through initiatives and referendums, the participatory democracy model does not describe democracy in America. Many Americans fear that a set of elite citizens is really in charge of government in the United States and that others have no influence. This belief is called the elite theory of government. Pluralist theorists (pluralist democracy model) assume that citizens who want to get involved in the system do so because of the great number of access points to government.</description></item><item><title>Authoritarian vs. Democratic Governments</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apgov/authoritarian-govts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apgov/authoritarian-govts/</guid><description>Authoritarian Governments Authoritarian governments are not constitutional governments. Constitutional governments are not governments that have constitutions. A constitutional government has a constitution that places limits on the government&amp;#39;s power and protects the people.
Characteristics of an authoritarian government Characterized by leadership that controls aspects of the citizens&amp;#39; lives Few political freedoms
Freedom of speech Freedom of assembly Due process
Procedures a government has to follow Media controlled by government Difficult to contain governmental corruption Democracy in Authoritarian Governments Authoritarian governments can sometimes have democratic features such as elections.</description></item><item><title>Politics</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apgov/politics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apgov/politics/</guid><description>Politics influences the way government takes action and makes policies.
Politics is Conflictual People will disagree on the way the government should handle certain issues. This turns the issues political.
For example, the idea of abortion itself is not a political issue. It is generally agreed among most people that abortion is the termination of a pregnancy. However, people are conflicted about the legalization of abortion. People have different ideas on the government&amp;#39;s involvement in the issue.</description></item></channel></rss>