<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notes</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/</link><description>Recent content on Notes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://notes.sandvich.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Conics</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/precalc/conics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/precalc/conics/</guid><description>Conic Sections degenerate conics - point, line parabola circle ellipse hyperbola Parabolas The distance between the focus and vertex is \(p\).
Every point on the parabola is equidistant from the focus to the directrix.
The latus rectum is a constant line that passes through the focus and parallel to the directrix. This line is \(4p\) units long.
\[ (x - h)^2 = 4p(y - k) \]
\[ y - k = \frac{(x - h)^2}{4p} \]</description></item><item><title>Chapter 4 - Analyzing Graphs</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apcalc/chapter-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apcalc/chapter-4/</guid><description>Extrema of a Function Absolute Extrema An absolute extremum can only exist in an open interval of $f$. A closed interval has an infinite amount of values that approach the start and end of the intervals, so it is impossible to define an exact extremum on a closed interval.
There may not be an absolute extremum in a function if the function is unbounded.
Local Extrema A local extremum exists at point $x$ if $f&amp;#39;(x) = 0$ with odd multiplicity (i.</description></item><item><title>Big Sheet</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apcalc/big-sheet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apcalc/big-sheet/</guid><description>Geometry Area Area of equilateral triangle $A = \frac{\sqrt{3}}{4} s^2$
Trapezoid $A = h \cdot \frac{1}{2}(b_1 + b_2)$
Surface Area Cylinder $\textrm{SA} = 2\pi r^2 + 2\pi r h$
Sphere $\textrm{SA} = 4\pi r^2$
Pythagorean Triples 3, 4, 5 5, 12, 13 7, 24, 25 8, 15, 17 Precalculus/Algebra Trig ratios for special angles \begin{array}{ r | c | c | c | c | c } f &amp;amp; 0 &amp;amp; \frac{\pi}{6} &amp;amp; \frac{\pi}{4} &amp;amp; \frac{\pi}{3} &amp;amp; \frac{\pi}{2} \\ \hline \sin &amp;amp; 0 &amp;amp; \frac{1}{2} &amp;amp; \frac{\sqrt{2}}{2} &amp;amp; \frac{\sqrt{3}}{2} &amp;amp; 1 \\ \cos &amp;amp; 1 &amp;amp; \frac{\sqrt{3}}{2} &amp;amp; \frac{\sqrt{2}}{2} &amp;amp; \frac{1}{2} &amp;amp; 0 \\ \tan &amp;amp; 0 &amp;amp; \frac{1}{\sqrt{3}} &amp;amp; 1 &amp;amp; \sqrt{3} &amp;amp; \textrm{undef} \\ \end{array}</description></item><item><title>Policy Making System</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apgov/policy-making-system/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apgov/policy-making-system/</guid><description>Elitism and Pluralism Although 24 states give voters the ability to directly vote on legislation through initiatives and referendums, the participatory democracy model does not describe democracy in America. Many Americans fear that a set of elite citizens is really in charge of government in the United States and that others have no influence. This belief is called the elite theory of government. Pluralist theorists (pluralist democracy model) assume that citizens who want to get involved in the system do so because of the great number of access points to government.</description></item><item><title>Authoritarian vs. Democratic Governments</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apgov/authoritarian-govts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apgov/authoritarian-govts/</guid><description>Authoritarian Governments Authoritarian governments are not constitutional governments. Constitutional governments are not governments that have constitutions. A constitutional government has a constitution that places limits on the government&amp;#39;s power and protects the people.
Characteristics of an authoritarian government Characterized by leadership that controls aspects of the citizens&amp;#39; lives Few political freedoms
Freedom of speech Freedom of assembly Due process
Procedures a government has to follow Media controlled by government Difficult to contain governmental corruption Democracy in Authoritarian Governments Authoritarian governments can sometimes have democratic features such as elections.</description></item><item><title>AWS Cloud Architect</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/cyber/aws-cloud-architecting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/cyber/aws-cloud-architecting/</guid><description>Introduction to Cloud Architecting What is Cloud Architecting? Origins of AWS To solve the problem of Amazon&amp;#39;s complicated web architecture, Amazon created AWS
Applications were built without proper planning It was difficult to separate services from each other Cloud Architecture Cloud architecture applies characteristics of the cloud to develop a solution using cloud services to meet an organization&amp;#39;s demands, like a blueprint or achitect in real life.
AWS services can easily create highly available, scalable, and reliable cloud architectures.</description></item><item><title>Politics</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apgov/politics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apgov/politics/</guid><description>Politics influences the way government takes action and makes policies.
Politics is Conflictual People will disagree on the way the government should handle certain issues. This turns the issues political.
For example, the idea of abortion itself is not a political issue. It is generally agreed among most people that abortion is the termination of a pregnancy. However, people are conflicted about the legalization of abortion. People have different ideas on the government&amp;#39;s involvement in the issue.</description></item><item><title>AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/cyber/aws-ccp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/cyber/aws-ccp/</guid><description>Cloud Concepts Introduction to Cloud Computing NIST Cloud Computing Definition On-demand self-service Broad netework access Resource pooling
Multi-tenant environments Rapid elasticity Measured service Service Models Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) Platform as a Service (PaaS) Software as a Service (SaaS) Deployment Models Private cloud Community cloud Public cloud Hybrid cloud Overview of Amazon Web Services Compute Amazon Elastic Compute (EC2) AWS Lambda Amazon Elastic Container Service (ECS) Storage Amazon Elastic Block Store (EBS) Amazon Simple Storage Service (S3) Amazon Glacier Application Services Amazon Simple Notification Service (SNS) Amazon Simple Email Service (SES) Amazon Simple Queue Service (SQS) Datastores Amazon Relational Database Service (RDS) Amazon DynamoDB Amazon ElastiCache Analytics Amazon Kinesis Amazon Elasticsearch Service Amazon Redshift Amazon EMR Amazon Athena Networking Amazon Virtual Private Cloud (VPC)</description></item><item><title>APUSH Period 7</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apush/period-7/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apush/period-7/</guid><description>Imperialism Reasons for imperialism Closing of the frontier Economic motives Racial theories Impacts of imperialism Spanish-American War
Causes
Yellow journalism (USS Maine) Imperialism, motive to protect Cubans and Filipinos Business interests with Cuba US gained Guam, Puerto Rico, Philippines
Insurrection in PH Debates about imperialism
Similar to interventionists and isolationists Progressive Era Progressives tended to be
Urban Middle Class Women Progressives sought to
Reform society socially and politically Use the federal government</description></item><item><title>APUSH Period 6</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apush/period-6/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apush/period-6/</guid><description>Gilded Age **
Social Effects More women more educated
As a result, more job opportunities opened for women Reform Edward Bellamy&amp;#39;s Looking Backward Was it possible to have an industrial society without great inequality?
Social Darwinists: no Responses to inequality New economic systems
Socialism
No private property Eugene V. Debs Single tax
Henry George Replace all other taxes with a single tax on the value of land Tax would pay for all necessary government expenditures Responses to urban problems Settlement house movement Social Gospel movement City Beautiful movement Politics Change and Continuity Work and business 1865 Farming, sharecropping Segregation Working in mills 1898 Farming and sharecropping Segregation Women&amp;#39;s and children&amp;#39;s labor Unions Mass production Living and migration patterns 1865 Most immigrants from Northern and Western Europe 20% of Americans lived in cities Some urban density and poverty 1898 Most immigrants from Southern and Eastern Europe 40% of Americans lived in cities Black migration High urban density and poverty Culture and ideas 1865 Nativism Intense push for racial equality Laissez-faire 1898 Nativism Little interest in racial equality Social Darwinism Review Topics Emergence of monopolies Social Darwinism Reasons for migration to cities New South New Immigration Labor unions The Grange Populists Westward Expansion</description></item><item><title>APUSH Period 5</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apush/period-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apush/period-5/</guid><description>Manifest Destiny Based on racial and cultural superiority Main focus of political debates Acquiring territory Mexican-American War Wilmot Proviso
Debates over slavery Impacts of Expansion Environmental changes Settlement of Indian lands Old Immigrants, pre-Civil War
Germans Irish Faced nativism
Know-nothing party Westward Expansion Opportunities out West
Increased due to legislation promoting economic development
Homestead Act of 1862 Impacts Conflicts with Hispanics and Natives
Sand Creek Massacre Little Big Horn North vs South North</description></item><item><title>Unit 8 - Ecology</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/unit-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/unit-8/</guid><description>Populations A population is a group of individuals of:
the same species in the same area at the same time rely on same resources Factors that affect population size Abiotic factors
Sunlight Precipitation / water Soil / nutrients Biotic factors
Prey Competitors Predators, parasites, disease Population Dispersion Clumped Most common Random Uniform May result from direct interactions Population Density Changes to pop size
Adding/removing individuals from a popultaion
Birth Death Immigration Emigration How can we measure population density?</description></item><item><title>APUSH Period 4</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apush/period-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apush/period-4/</guid><description>Increased Democracy and Government Relationships Emergence of Political Parties
Federalists vs. Democratic-Republican (1790s)
Hamilton vs. Jefferson Democrats vs. Whigs (1830s - 1850s)
Jackson vs. Clay Supreme Court increased the power of the federal government over states
McCulloch v. Maryland Worcester v. Georgia Growth of market economy
Embargo Act of 1807 Nullification Crisis of 1832 South justified slavery as a &amp;#34;positive good&amp;#34; New Institutions 2nd Great Awakening
Stressed importance of achieving perfection Reform movenets</description></item><item><title>Unit 7 - Natural Selection</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/unit-7/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/unit-7/</guid><description>Population Genetics The gene pool is the sum of alleles within a population A population is a localized group of organisms of the same species Impacts on a Population Changes in frequency often indicate evolution Small populations are more susceptible to random impact than large populations
Small gene pool Less variation within gene pool Genetic Drift Genetic dift is the random fluctuation in allele frequency between generations.
Founder Effect A very small population is isolated from a major population The small population may have less genetic variation Genetic Bottleneck In a genetic bottleneck, allele frequency is altered due to a population crash.</description></item><item><title>Derivative Basics</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/precalc/derivatives/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/precalc/derivatives/</guid><description>Derivatives The derivative of a function \(f&amp;#39;(x)\) describes the instantaneous slope of a function \(f(x)\) at a given \(x\).
For example, at the constant function \(f(x) = b\), the derivative of the function would be \(f&amp;#39;(x) = 0\) as there is no slope in the function. At the linear function \(f(x) = mx + b\), the derivative of the function would be \(f&amp;#39;(x) = m\) since the slope is constantly \(m\).</description></item><item><title>Limits</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/precalc/limits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/precalc/limits/</guid><description>Introduction to Calculus Three parts of calculus Limits Calculus approach to mathematics G - graphical/geometric N - numerical A - analytical/algebraic W - words Introduction to Limits What can occur in $f(x)$ at an arbitrarily value of $x$? Removable discontinuity Vertical asymptote Jump discontinuity A point What are examples of approaching? History grade approaching zero Russia approaching Ukraine Queen Elizabeth approaching immortality Approaching = going towards, whether it will make it or not Examples Example 1 $$ \lim_{x \to 1} \frac{x^3 - 1}{x - 1} $$</description></item><item><title>Essay: Identify, Protect, Detect, Respond, Recover</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/cyber/ipdrr/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/cyber/ipdrr/</guid><description>Introduction The sole job of Cybersecurity is to identify and mitigate risk. Cybersecurity does not accept risk at all, but we bring it to an acceptable level towards upper management. But in order to identify and mitigate risk, we must follow a set of guidelines to help protect our systems and networks. Fortunately, NIST has developed the Cybersecurity Framework which sets a standard and describes the appropriate steps to developing a well-organized cybersecurity program.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 8 - Sequences</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/precalc/chapter-8/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/precalc/chapter-8/</guid><description>A sequence is a collection of terms that follows a general rule, or an equation, which develops a pattern.
term - element of a sequence General Rule \[ a_n = \frac{(-1)^n}{2n - 1} \]
Where \(n\) is the term number, and \(n\) must be a positive integer.
\[ a_1 = \frac{(-1)^1}{2(1) - 1} = -1 \],
\[ a_2 = \frac{(-1)^2}{2(2) - 1} = \frac{1}{3} \],
\[ a_3 = \frac{(-1)^3}{2(3) - 1} = -\frac{1}{5} \],</description></item><item><title>Chapter 7 - Matrices</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/precalc/chapter-7/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/precalc/chapter-7/</guid><description>Solving Systems of Equations Solving by graphing Solving by substitution Solving by elimination Solving Multivariable Systems of Equations Row-echelon form Row Operations Interchange any two equations Multiply an equation by a non-zero constant Add an equation to another equation Partial Fraction Decomposition A rational expression can often be written as the sum of two or more simpler rational expressions (fractions).
Example \(\frac{x + 7}{x^2 - x - 6} = \frac{x + 7}{(x - 3)(x + 2)}\) \[ \frac{A}{x - 3} + \frac{B}{x + 2} \]</description></item><item><title>Chapter 6 - Vectors</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/precalc/chapter-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/precalc/chapter-6/</guid><description>6.1 Law of Sines \[ \sin \frac{A}{a} = \sin \frac{B}{b} = \sin \frac{C}{c} \]
The Law of Sines works best with AAS and ASA triangles.
It can work with SSA triangles. It may give you two solutions, one solution, or no solution at all.
Area of a Triangle \[ A = \frac{1}{2}ab \sin C\]
Examples Given \(a = 7\), \(b = 6,\) and \(A = 26.3^\circ\), find \(B\).
\(B = 22.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 5 - Trigonometric Equations</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/precalc/chapter-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/precalc/chapter-5/</guid><description>5.3 Solving Trigonometric Equations Solve \(2\sin x - 1\) \[ 2\sin x = 1 \]
\[ \sin x = \frac{1}{2} \]
\[ x = \frac{\pi}{6} + 2\pi k\]
Solve \(\sin x + \sqrt{2} = -\sin x\) \[ 2sin x = -\sqrt{2} \]
\[ sin x = -\frac{\sqrt{2}}{2} \]
\[ x = -\frac{\pi}{3} + 2\pi k \]
Solve \(3\tan^2 x - 1 = 0\) \[ \tan^2 x = \frac{1}{3} \]</description></item><item><title>Chapter 3 - Exponential Functions</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/precalc/chapter-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/precalc/chapter-3/</guid><description>3.1 Exponential Functions and Their Graphs Linear vs Exponential Growth Linear functions grow at a constant rate.
An exponential function grows by a multiple of its current value.
Example Using the equation \(y = a(2)^{b(x-c)} + d\), change the values of \(a, b, c, d\) and determine the effects of them on the graph.
\(a\) vertically dilates the graph \(b\) horizontally compresses the graph \(c\) horizontally translates the graph \(d\) vertically translates the graph Euler&amp;#39;s Number Create the graph of \(y = (\frac{1}{x})^x\).</description></item><item><title>Chapter 2 - Polynomials</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/precalc/chapter-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/precalc/chapter-2/</guid><description>2.1 Polynomials A polynomial is an equation with multiple terms. Exact definitions may very, but multiple terms may be either 4+ terms, or 1+ terms. It is mostly agreed upon that a polynomial is an umbrella term that also captures monomials, binomials, and trinomials.
All polynomials can not have negative or fraction exponents.
\[ ax^n + ... + c \]
Quadratic Functions A quadratic function is a function whose highest degree is the second power.</description></item><item><title>Unit 4</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apwh/unit_4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apwh/unit_4/</guid><description>Advancement of Maritime Technology Europeans could not travel to South Asia through land since Muslim empires controlled land trade routes. Fluyt Caravel Carrick Technologies introduced to Europeans:
Lateen sail Astronomical charts Astrolabe Magnetic compass The New World Christopher Columbus landed in the Carribean Islands Developed the Columbian Exchange Columbian Exchange Disease
Smallpox Measles Malaria Crops
Sugar and horses to Americas Potatoes, maize, guinea pigs to Europe Atlantic Slave Trade</description></item><item><title>Unit 5</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apwh/unit_5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apwh/unit_5/</guid><description>Enlightenment Philosophers of the Enlightenment started to push out ideas of social and political structure at the time
Locke - Natural rights, right to overthrow governments Rousseau - Social contract Montesquieu - Separation of powers Voltaire - Free speech and religious toleration Feminism Revolutions
All revolutions were inspired by the Enlightenment American Revolution
Constitution and Bill of Rights with Enlightenment ideas Inspired other revolutions Declaration of Independence
&amp;#34;It is the Right of the People to alter or abolish [the Government].</description></item><item><title>Unit 6</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apwh/unit_6/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apwh/unit_6/</guid><description>Imperialism Economic and political dominance Motives behind imperialism:
Money (raw materials for production) Social Darwinism and &amp;#34;White Man&amp;#39;s Burden&amp;#34; Nationalism Desire to spread Christianity
Most empires usually used this as an excuse, however Berlin Conference
Otto von Bismarck negotiated which countries would have which partitions of Africa Countries that industrialized earlier had significantly more colonies Responses to Imperialism Some colonies attempted to negotiate with Europeans
&amp;#34;The suggestion that Ashanti in its present state should come and enjoy the protection of Her Majesty the Queen of England and Empress of India is a matter of very serious consideration.</description></item><item><title>Unit 2</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apwh/unit_2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apwh/unit_2/</guid><description>Silk Road connected China to Europe and passed through Southwest Asia Indian Ocean connected East Asia with East Africa and passed through Southeast and South Asia Trans-Saharan connected North Africa to sub-Saharan Africa Similarities Between Trade Routes Depended on establishments of large states (e.g. Mongols and Silk Road) New technologies
Magnetic compass Lateen sail Stern-post rudder Missionaries Introduction of new crops to new places Growth of trading cities Spread of culture and cross-cultural exchanges Differences Between Trade Routes Different technologies and methods of transportation Different religions were spread among different trade routes Similarities and Differences Chart Goods Technology Religion Silk Roads Silk, Porcelain, Gunpowder, Horses, Textiles Saddles, Caravanserai Buddhism, Neoconfucianism, Islam Indian Ocean Gold, Ivory, Fruit, Textiles, Pepper, Rice Astrolabe, Compass, Sternpost Rudder, Lateen Sail Christianity, Buddhism, Neoconfucianism, Islam Trans-Saharan Horses, Salt, Gold, Slaves Saddles Islam Cultural Consequences Zen Buddhism originated from China but spread to Korea and Vietnam African Bantu converted to Islam</description></item><item><title>Unit 3</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apwh/unit_3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apwh/unit_3/</guid><description>Qing Dynasty Mughal Empire Ottoman Empire Safavid Empire Consolidating Power Qing Dynasty consolidated power through the Civil Service Exam
The Qing Dynasty was set up by the Manchu people who were foreigners to China To consolidate power, the leader and people would have to think the same Ottomans used the Devshirme system
Enslaved poor Christian boys from Southern Europe and the Balkans Received thorough education Became bureaucratic workers or served in the military (Janissaries) Ottomans used Tax Farming</description></item><item><title>Unit 1</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apwh/unit_1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apwh/unit_1/</guid><description>Process of State Building Across States Song Dynasty The Chinese during this period greatly flourished due to cultural and technological advancements.
Technological Advancement
Gunpowder Grand Canal Champa Rice Cultural Advancement
Revival of Confucianism Revival of Civil Service Exam Delhi Sultanate Established by Muslim Turks Had a difficult time converting Indian society to Islam Mamluk Sultanate Formerly a slave empire Non-Muslims were enslaved by the Egyptians and forced to serve in the military Mamluks then overthrew the government and established the Mamluk Sultanate The Vijayanagara Empire built their states and expanded their influence by means of trade.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 3 - Displaying Categorical Data</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-3/</guid><description>Categorical data, also known as qualitative data, is data that can be divided into categories or qualities
Vocabulary frequency table - a table that shows how frequent a specific category is proportion - describes the quantity of the frequency relative frequency distribution - what proportion did something happen distribution - how the data is spread out, usually how it is spread out graphically area principle - contingency table - a table that displays data involving several independent variables marginal distribution - a distribution that takes in the totals of contingency data conditional distribution - a distribution that takes in a condition (e.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 4 - Quantitative Data</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-4/</guid><description>Vocabulary histogram - a graph that displays values over a quantitative interval bin - an interval relative frequency histogram stem and leaf plot dot plot outlier Histogram A histogram, like all other graphs, requires a specific title. Like a bar graph, the y-axis is the dependent variable (usually the frequency), and the x-axis is an interval of quantitative data known as bins.
A scale marking on the x-axis must describe an exact value.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 5</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-5/</guid><description>Standard Deviation By definition, the standard deviation $s$ is known as the square root of the variance $s^2$ of a dataset.
\[ s^2 = \frac{\Sigma(x - \bar{x})^2}{n - 1} \]
import math data = [ 5, 11, 12, 17, 22 ] def mean(): sum_of_list = 0 for x in data: sum_of_list += x return sum_of_list / len(data) def std_dev(): sigma = 0 mean_of_data = mean() for x in data: sigma += pow(x - mean_of_data, 2) return math.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 5 - Untitled</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apcalc/chapter-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apcalc/chapter-5/</guid><description>Optimization Assign symbols to all given quantities and quantities to be determined. Make a sketch (if possible). Write a PRIMARY EQUATION for the quantity being maximized or minimized. (Call this M.) Reduce the primary equation to one having a single independent variable. Determine the maximum/minimum using critical values. Use the first (or second) derivative test and choose the feasible answer. Be sure to answer the question asked. Include units (if applicable).</description></item><item><title>Chapter 6 - Standard Deviation as a Ruler &amp; Normal Model</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-6/</guid><description>Z-Score \[ Z = \frac{x - \bar{x}}{S} \]
$x$ is the data value
$\bar{x}$ is the mean
$S$ is the standard deviation
The z-score is essentially a ratio of a given datapoint&amp;#39;s deviation to the standard deviation.
This can only be applied to normally or approximately normally distributed data.
Example At a selective college, two professors, Dr. V and Dr. W, have a competition to see who can give the most difficult tests in Calculus I.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 7 - Scatterplots, Association, and Correlation</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-7/</guid><description>Scatterplot A scatterplot displays a set of ordered pairs. It is a common way of displaying two-variable data.
Scatterplots can have varying degrees of linearity.
Random scatter - no pattern can be determined in the data Positive relationship - positive slope Negative relationship - negative slope Important Ideas Association
linear non-linear Correlation - only use correlation if there is a linear association
positive negative constant Strength - how &amp;#34;strong&amp;#34; or tight the linear correlation is</description></item><item><title>Potential LEQ Topics</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apush/potential-leq-topics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apush/potential-leq-topics/</guid><description>Triangular Trade Causes
Desire for goods/trade (economic) Desire to develop colonies (political) Demand for slave labor Effects
Introduction of new crops Development of colonies Further demand for slave labor Exchange of culture Market Revolution Causes and effects are mostly similar; you can interchange causes and effects unless asked to compare the causes and effects Causes
Rapid improvements of transportation and communication Industrial machines and inventions Increased federal power Effects</description></item></channel></rss>