<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AP Statistics on Notes</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/</link><description>Recent content in AP Statistics on Notes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chapter 19 - Confidence</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-19/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-19/</guid><description>Tradeoffs The higher the confidence level is, the lower the precision will be.
Examples Example 2 A TV news reporter states the results of a poll of voters, and then says, &amp;#34;the margin of error is plus or minus 4%&amp;#34;
There is a 95% confidence that the response of the population is 4 percent away from response of the sample.
Example 2 Police set up an auto checkpoint at which drivers are stopped and their cars are inspected for safety problems.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 18 - Sampling Distribution</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-18/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-18/</guid><description>Sampling distributions can be most useful with a normal curve. In order to make this assumption, certain conditions need to be met.
Randomization
the sampling method must be known to be random and guarantee normality Independence of selections
Independence must be stated or implied OR no more than 10% of the population must be sampled Large enough sample condition
For proportions: there must be at least 10 succcesses $np$ and at least 10 failures $n(1 - p)$ which keeps us away from heavily skewed situations For means: central limit theorem</description></item><item><title>Chapter 17 - Probability Models</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-17/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-17/</guid><description>Geometric Probability Model Peopel with O-negative blood are called &amp;#34;universal donors&amp;#34; because O-negative blood can be given to anyone else. Only about 6% of poeple have O-negative blood. How many people would you expect to examine before finding someone wiht O-negative.
\[ \frac{1}{0.06} = 16.67\% \]
Here&amp;#39;s why this is geometric:
There are two outcomes: O-negative blood or NOT O-negative blood The probability of success is the same for each person Trials either need to be independent OR contain less thna 10% of hte total population Looking for the first successful outcome Syntax geompdf(p, x) - Geometric distribution at a point</description></item><item><title>Chapter 16 - Random Variables</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-16/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-16/</guid><description>Discrete vs Continuous A discrete random variable has a countable number of outcomes. A continuous random variable can occur in infinitely many ways.
A continuous variable can fall anywhere within an interval, but a discrete variable must fall into a specific place.
Expected Value An expected value of a variable can be based on a probability distribution.
Here is an example with life insurance.
Outcome Payout Probability Death $10000 1/1000 Disability $5000 2/1000 Neither $0 997/1000 \[ E(x) = 1E4(\frac{1}{1E3}) + 5E3(\frac{2}{2E3}) + 0(\frac{997}{1E3}) = 20 \]</description></item><item><title>Chapter 14 - Randomness to Probability</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-14/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-14/</guid><description>Vocabulary independent event - an event that is not influenced by another event disjoint event - mtually exclusive law of large numbers - in probability, more trials matches the experimental probability to the theoretical probability union - $\cup$ &amp;#34;or&amp;#34; intersection - $\cap$ &amp;#34;and&amp;#34; complement - $A^c$ &amp;#34;not&amp;#34; addition rule - $P(A) + P(B) = P(A \cup B)$ if A and B are mutually exclusive
otherwise, $P(A) + P(B) - P(A \cap B) = P(A \cup B)$ multiplication rule - $P(A)P(B) = P(A \cap B)$ Independent Events If two events A and B are independent, then</description></item><item><title>Chapter 13 - Experimental Design</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-13/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-13/</guid><description>Vocabulary Briefing Lurking and Confounding Variables Lurking and Confounding Variables Lurking variable is a variable that is not explicitly included in the analysis, but which may influence the results of the analysis. Confounding variable is a variable that is not of interest in the analysis, but which may influence the results of the analysis.
Example of a lurking variable:
The study is investigating the effect of stress on health. The stress variable is measured, but the study does not measure the health of the participants.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 12 - Sample Surveys</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-12/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-12/</guid><description>Sample surveys occur in the real world in the form of opinion polls.
A well-constructed sample survey can provide useful information, but it is very possible to fail to set up a reasonable survey and create results that are far from the intended truth.
For example, a Literary Digest poll surveyed 10 million people that would predict Alf Landon winning the 1936 U.S. Election over Franklin D. Roosevelt. However, those 10 million surveyees came from a phone book and drivers&amp;#39; registrations.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 11 - Simulations</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-11/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-11/</guid><description> Identify the simulated item (component) How will you model the outcome? What is a successful trial? How will you simulate the randomness? State clearly what your response variable is Run several trials
The more trials you run, the more the data is likely to resemble statistical truth
Regression to the mean Law of large numbers Analyze the response variable data Write an analysis and conclusion</description></item><item><title>Chapter 9 &amp; 10 - Regression Wisdom, Re-expression of Data</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-9-10/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-9-10/</guid><description>Slightly Curved Data Some slightly curved data appears to be linear and possesses a high correlation coefficient. However, the curve of the data will reveal itself in the residuals, which would produce a curved pattern.
Leverage, Influence, and Outliers Unusual features on a scatterplot exert too much influence on the linear regression. Sometimes these features display a pattern that isn&amp;#39;t actually there. Sometimes it brings the regression line towards its location.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 8 - Linear Regression</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-8/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-8/</guid><description>Line of Best Fit \[ \hat{y} = a + bx \]
Points on the line of best fit are predicted y-values, which is why $\hat{y}$ notation is used.
The value of $r^2$ is the percent of the data&amp;#39;s variation in the y-value that is accounted for by the variation of the x-value.
Example Explanatory variable: miles traveled in a car
Response variable: gallons of gasoline used
R-squared value: 0.87</description></item><item><title>Chapter 7 - Scatterplots, Association, and Correlation</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-7/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-7/</guid><description>Scatterplot A scatterplot displays a set of ordered pairs. It is a common way of displaying two-variable data.
Scatterplots can have varying degrees of linearity.
Random scatter - no pattern can be determined in the data Positive relationship - positive slope Negative relationship - negative slope Important Ideas Association
linear non-linear Correlation - only use correlation if there is a linear association
positive negative constant Strength - how &amp;#34;strong&amp;#34; or tight the linear correlation is</description></item><item><title>Chapter 3 - Displaying Categorical Data</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-3/</guid><description>Categorical data, also known as qualitative data, is data that can be divided into categories or qualities
Vocabulary frequency table - a table that shows how frequent a specific category is proportion - describes the quantity of the frequency relative frequency distribution - what proportion did something happen distribution - how the data is spread out, usually how it is spread out graphically area principle - contingency table - a table that displays data involving several independent variables marginal distribution - a distribution that takes in the totals of contingency data conditional distribution - a distribution that takes in a condition (e.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 4 - Quantitative Data</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-4/</guid><description>Vocabulary histogram - a graph that displays values over a quantitative interval bin - an interval relative frequency histogram stem and leaf plot dot plot outlier Histogram A histogram, like all other graphs, requires a specific title. Like a bar graph, the y-axis is the dependent variable (usually the frequency), and the x-axis is an interval of quantitative data known as bins.
A scale marking on the x-axis must describe an exact value.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 5</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-5/</guid><description>Standard Deviation By definition, the standard deviation $s$ is known as the square root of the variance $s^2$ of a dataset.
\[ s^2 = \frac{\Sigma(x - \bar{x})^2}{n - 1} \]
import math data = [ 5, 11, 12, 17, 22 ] def mean(): sum_of_list = 0 for x in data: sum_of_list += x return sum_of_list / len(data) def std_dev(): sigma = 0 mean_of_data = mean() for x in data: sigma += pow(x - mean_of_data, 2) return math.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 6 - Standard Deviation as a Ruler &amp; Normal Model</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-6/</guid><description>Z-Score \[ Z = \frac{x - \bar{x}}{S} \]
$x$ is the data value
$\bar{x}$ is the mean
$S$ is the standard deviation
The z-score is essentially a ratio of a given datapoint&amp;#39;s deviation to the standard deviation.
This can only be applied to normally or approximately normally distributed data.
Example At a selective college, two professors, Dr. V and Dr. W, have a competition to see who can give the most difficult tests in Calculus I.</description></item></channel></rss>