<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AP Statistics on Notes</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/</link><description>Recent content in AP Statistics on Notes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chapter 3 - Displaying Categorical Data</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-3/</guid><description>Categorical data, also known as qualitative data, is data that can be divided into categories or qualities
Vocabulary frequency table - a table that shows how frequent a specific category is proportion - describes the quantity of the frequency relative frequency distribution - what proportion did something happen distribution - how the data is spread out, usually how it is spread out graphically area principle - contingency table - a table that displays data involving several independent variables marginal distribution - a distribution that takes in the totals of contingency data conditional distribution - a distribution that takes in a condition (e.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 4 - Quantitative Data</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-4/</guid><description>Vocabulary histogram - a graph that displays values over a quantitative interval bin - an interval relative frequency histogram stem and leaf plot dot plot outlier Histogram A histogram, like all other graphs, requires a specific title. Like a bar graph, the y-axis is the dependent variable (usually the frequency), and the x-axis is an interval of quantitative data known as bins.
A scale marking on the x-axis must describe an exact value.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 5</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-5/</guid><description>Standard Deviation By definition, the standard deviation $s$ is known as the square root of the variance $s^2$ of a dataset.
\[ s^2 = \frac{\Sigma(x - \bar{x})^2}{n - 1} \]
import math data = [ 5, 11, 12, 17, 22 ] def mean(): sum_of_list = 0 for x in data: sum_of_list += x return sum_of_list / len(data) def std_dev(): sigma = 0 mean_of_data = mean() for x in data: sigma += pow(x - mean_of_data, 2) return math.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 6 - Standard Deviation as a Ruler &amp; Normal Model</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-6/</guid><description>Z-Score \[ Z = \frac{x - \bar{x}}{S} \]
$x$ is the data value
$\bar{x}$ is the mean
$S$ is the standard deviation
The z-score is essentially a ratio of a given datapoint&amp;#39;s deviation to the standard deviation.
This can only be applied to normally or approximately normally distributed data.
Example At a selective college, two professors, Dr. V and Dr. W, have a competition to see who can give the most difficult tests in Calculus I.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 7 - Scatterplots, Association, and Correlation</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apstats/chapter-7/</guid><description>Scatterplot A scatterplot displays a set of ordered pairs. It is a common way of displaying two-variable data.
Scatterplots can have varying degrees of linearity.
Random scatter - no pattern can be determined in the data Positive relationship - positive slope Negative relationship - negative slope Important Ideas Association
linear non-linear Correlation - only use correlation if there is a linear association
positive negative constant Strength - how &amp;#34;strong&amp;#34; or tight the linear correlation is</description></item></channel></rss>