<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cybersecurity &amp; AWS Cloud on Notes</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/cyber/</link><description>Recent content in Cybersecurity &amp; AWS Cloud on Notes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://notes.sandvich.xyz/cyber/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Subnetting</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/cyber/subnetting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/cyber/subnetting/</guid><description>Subnetting takes a network and divides it into subnetworks.
Example:
10.0.0.x/24 splits into 10.0.0.0 to 10.0.0.255
10.0.0.x/25 splits the network into two equal subnets: 10.0.0.0 to 10.0.0.127 and 10.0.0.128 to 10.0.0.255
10.0.0.x/26 further splits those two parts into four equal subnets.
Attributes of Subnetting Number of IP addresses
How many addresses in the network CIDR/Subnet
The subnet mask that divides a network (and its CIDR notation equivalent) Network ID</description></item><item><title>AWS Cloud Architect</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/cyber/aws-cloud-architecting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/cyber/aws-cloud-architecting/</guid><description>Introduction to Cloud Architecting What is Cloud Architecting? Origins of AWS To solve the problem of Amazon&amp;#39;s complicated web architecture, Amazon created AWS
Applications were built without proper planning It was difficult to separate services from each other Cloud Architecture Cloud architecture applies characteristics of the cloud to develop a solution using cloud services to meet an organization&amp;#39;s demands, like a blueprint or achitect in real life.
AWS services can easily create highly available, scalable, and reliable cloud architectures.</description></item><item><title>AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/cyber/aws-ccp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/cyber/aws-ccp/</guid><description>Cloud Concepts Introduction to Cloud Computing NIST Cloud Computing Definition On-demand self-service Broad netework access Resource pooling
Multi-tenant environments Rapid elasticity Measured service Service Models Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) Platform as a Service (PaaS) Software as a Service (SaaS) Deployment Models Private cloud Community cloud Public cloud Hybrid cloud Overview of Amazon Web Services Compute Amazon Elastic Compute (EC2) AWS Lambda Amazon Elastic Container Service (ECS) Storage Amazon Elastic Block Store (EBS) Amazon Simple Storage Service (S3) Amazon Glacier Application Services Amazon Simple Notification Service (SNS) Amazon Simple Email Service (SES) Amazon Simple Queue Service (SQS) Datastores Amazon Relational Database Service (RDS) Amazon DynamoDB Amazon ElastiCache Analytics Amazon Kinesis Amazon Elasticsearch Service Amazon Redshift Amazon EMR Amazon Athena Networking Amazon Virtual Private Cloud (VPC)</description></item><item><title>Essay: Identify, Protect, Detect, Respond, Recover</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/cyber/ipdrr/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/cyber/ipdrr/</guid><description>Introduction The sole job of Cybersecurity is to identify and mitigate risk. Cybersecurity does not accept risk at all, but we bring it to an acceptable level towards upper management. But in order to identify and mitigate risk, we must follow a set of guidelines to help protect our systems and networks. Fortunately, NIST has developed the Cybersecurity Framework which sets a standard and describes the appropriate steps to developing a well-organized cybersecurity program.</description></item></channel></rss>