<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AP Biology on Notes</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/</link><description>Recent content in AP Biology on Notes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unit 8 - Ecology</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/unit-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/unit-8/</guid><description>Populations A population is a group of individuals of:
the same species in the same area at the same time rely on same resources Factors that affect population size Abiotic factors
Sunlight Precipitation / water Soil / nutrients Biotic factors
Prey Competitors Predators, parasites, disease Population Dispersion Clumped Most common Random Uniform May result from direct interactions Population Density Changes to pop size
Adding/removing individuals from a popultaion
Birth Death Immigration Emigration How can we measure population density?</description></item><item><title>Unit 7 - Natural Selection</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/unit-7/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/unit-7/</guid><description>Population Genetics The gene pool is the sum of alleles within a population A population is a localized group of organisms of the same species Impacts on a Population Changes in frequency often indicate evolution Small populations are more susceptible to random impact than large populations
Small gene pool Less variation within gene pool Genetic Drift Genetic dift is the random fluctuation in allele frequency between generations.
Founder Effect A very small population is isolated from a major population The small population may have less genetic variation Genetic Bottleneck In a genetic bottleneck, allele frequency is altered due to a population crash.</description></item><item><title>Cellular Respiration</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/08-respiration/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/08-respiration/</guid><description>Cellular Respiration Produces CO2 and ATP Glycolysis Does not require oxygen Happens in both aerobic and anaerobic respiration Glucose as input Makes ATP C6 -&amp;gt; 2C3 (costs 2 ATP) C3 + NAD+ + ADP -&amp;gt; Pyruvate + NADH + 2ATP Process happens for each C3, total 4ATP Net gain: 2 ATP Anaerobic Total of 4 ATP Fermentation Produces 2 ATP Lactic acid fermentation 2 Pyruvic Acid + 2 NADH -&amp;gt; 2 Lactic Acid + 2 NAD+ Ethanol fermentation Yeast, etc.</description></item><item><title>Energetics</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/07-energetics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/07-energetics/</guid><description>1st and 2nd Laws of Thermodynamics &amp;ldquo;Energy can be transferred or transformed but neither created nor destroyed.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Every energy transfer or transformation increases the disorder (entropy) of the universe.&amp;rdquo; Organisms are Energy Transformers Organisms:
Transform energy to new forms (1st law) Free Energy Free energy is energy available to do work.
Metabolic Reactions Exergonic reactions release free energy Endergonic reactions absorb free energy</description></item><item><title>Water Potential</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/06-water-potential/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/06-water-potential/</guid><description>Water potential is the measure of the free energy of water. It is the force responsible for movement of water in a system.
Has the symbol psi \psi Measured in bars or megapascals (MPa) Components Pressure potential $\psi _s$ Results from exertion of pressure Solute potential $\psi _p$ Determined by solute concentration Calculating Water Potential $$ \psi = \psi _p = \psi _s $$
Standard for measuring $\psi$ Pure water is the standard.</description></item><item><title>Osmosis</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/05-osmosis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/05-osmosis/</guid><description>Managing water balance Cell survival depends on balancing water uptake and loss Hypertonic Low concentration of water around cell Animal cells die Hypotonic High concentration of water around cell Animal cells burst Plant cells become rigid Isotonic No difference in concentration Cells function normally</description></item><item><title>Chemistry of Carbon</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/04-chemistry-of-carbon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/04-chemistry-of-carbon/</guid><description>Organic Chemistry Organic chemistry is the study of carbon compounds. Carbon atoms are versatile building blocks 4 stable covalent bonds All of life is built on carbon Cells are made of ~72% H2O ~25% carbon compounds Carbohydrates Lipids Proteins Nucleic Acids ~3% salts Organic Chemistry Nomenclature 1 = Meth
2 = Eth
3 = Prop
4 = Bute
5+ = greek prefixes (penta, hexa, etc.)
Name Type of bond Chemical Formula N-ane Single bond CnH2n + 2 N-ene Double bond CnH2n N-yne Triple bond CnHn Carbon and Multiple Bonding It can share four pairs of electrons in four covalent bonds.</description></item><item><title>Claim Evidence Reasoning</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/03-cer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/03-cer/</guid><description>CER Breakdown Claim - what do you know? Evidence - how do you know that? Reasoning - why does your evidence support your claim? Claim Statement that answers your question Evidence Data to back up your claim Reasoning Connects your evidence to the claim Examples Claim My dad is an alien This statement answers the question Evidence He speaks a weird language This is factual and true Reasoning Aliens are not from Earth, so they have their own language This proves why the evidence supports the claim</description></item><item><title>Chi Squared Test</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/02-chisquared/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/02-chisquared/</guid><description>Hypotheses A hypothesis is a statement of the researcher&amp;rsquo;s idea or guess To test a hypothesis, the first thing to do is write a statement called the null hypothesis The null hypothesis is often the opposite of the researcher&amp;rsquo;s guess Example Null hypothesis: *There is no difference between the average number of streams per square kilometer and the bedrock type.
Alternative hypotheses: *There is a difference between the average number of streams per square kilometer and the bedrock type.</description></item><item><title>Standard Deviation and Standard Error</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/01-stddev-stderr/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/01-stddev-stderr/</guid><description>Standard Deviation Standard deviation measures how spread out the data is.
A lower standard deviation: - Data is closer to the mean - The independent variable may be causing the changes in the dependent variable
A higher standard deviation: - Data is more spread out from the mean - Factors other than the independent variable may be causing the changes in the dependent variable
To calculate standard deviation $s$
$$ s = \sqrt{\frac{\Sigma (x_i - \overline{x})^2}{n - 1}} $$</description></item><item><title/><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/unit-06/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/unit-06/</guid><description>% Unit 6: Heredity
Meiosis I</description></item></channel></rss>