<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apbio on Notes</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/</link><description>Recent content in Apbio on Notes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unit 8 - Ecology</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/unit-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/unit-8/</guid><description>Populations A population is a group of individuals of:
the same species in the same area at the same time rely on same resources Factors that affect population size Abiotic factors
Sunlight Precipitation / water Soil / nutrients Biotic factors
Prey Competitors Predators, parasites, disease Population Dispersion Clumped Most common Random Uniform May result from direct interactions Population Density Changes to pop size
Adding/removing individuals from a popultaion
Birth Death Immigration Emigration How can we measure population density?</description></item><item><title>Unit 7 - Natural Selection</title><link>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/unit-7/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.sandvich.xyz/apbio/unit-7/</guid><description>Population Genetics The gene pool is the sum of alleles within a population A population is a localized group of organisms of the same species Impacts on a Population Changes in frequency often indicate evolution Small populations are more susceptible to random impact than large populations
Small gene pool Less variation within gene pool Genetic Drift Genetic dift is the random fluctuation in allele frequency between generations.
Founder Effect A very small population is isolated from a major population The small population may have less genetic variation Genetic Bottleneck In a genetic bottleneck, allele frequency is altered due to a population crash.</description></item></channel></rss>